[
    {
        "question": "Which country owns the Canary Islands?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What color is the bottom strip of Egypt`s flag?",
        "answer": "Black"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city in Tennessee is the country music capital?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of New York State?",
        "answer": "Albany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What lake is located between Lake Huron and Lake Erie?",
        "answer": "Lake St. Clair"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which states share a border with South Carolina?",
        "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Treasure State`?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What large US city is located near Lake Mead?",
        "answer": "Las Vegas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Tennessee?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three states share a border with Michigan?",
        "answer": "Indiana, Ohio and Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river`s water is controlled by the Aswan Dam?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country can a man be referred to as `First Footer`?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Arab country houses the Rub Al-Khali or Empty Quarter, the largest continuous sand desert in the world?",
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "What region makes up 75% of Russia?",
        "answer": "Siberia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Arab country`s flag has a green cedar tree in the center?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African state fought a 31-year war for independence from Ethiopia?",
        "answer": "Eritrea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country was occupied by Britain from 1814 until 1964?",
        "answer": "Malta"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the original name of Denali?",
        "answer": "Denali -- The name was changed to Mt. McKinley in 1896 after then-presidential candidate William McKinley."
    },
    {
        "question": "What do Ireland and St. Lucia island have in common?",
        "answer": "Both are named after historical women -- Saint Lucia got its name from Saint Lucy of Syracuse. Ireland is named after Erui, an ancient Irish mythological goddess."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state is home to the American bison?",
        "answer": "South Dakota -- It is home to more than 33,000 bison making the state home to the most. It is a fraction of the 60 million that once roamed the country."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world\u00b4s newest country as of 2023?",
        "answer": "South Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Burkina Faso?",
        "answer": "Ouagadougou"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries are contained in the country of South Africa?",
        "answer": "Eswatini and Lesotho"
    },
    {
        "question": "What substance gives the White Cliffs of Dover their color?",
        "answer": "Chalk"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the \u201cyou are here\u201d sign on a map properly called?",
        "answer": "Ideolocater"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nicosia is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cyprus"
    },
    {
        "question": "The island country Cyprus, lies within what water body?",
        "answer": "Mediterranean Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "The island country Cyprus lies south of what country?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Michigan?",
        "answer": "Lansing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Canberra`s Telstra Tower also known as?",
        "answer": "Black Mountain Tower"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do Scandinavian country flags have in common?",
        "answer": "Crosses -- The Scandinavian flags use different colors and slightly different designs, but they all feature one thing in common: a Nordic cross."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the highest tides located?",
        "answer": "Bay of Fundy, Canada -- It sees over 175 billion tons of seawater flowing in and out with the tides, an amount greater than the combined amount of all the freshwater rivers on Earth."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the original Jersey?",
        "answer": "The original Jersey is an island in the English Channel that is a self-governing British crown dependency. It is the largest of Channel Islands, located just 12 miles off the coast of France."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is there an airport named for the creator of the `Peanuts` Comics?",
        "answer": "Santa Rosa, California -- The comics were created by Charles M. Schulz. After his death in 2000, Santa Rosa`s airport was renamed Charles M. Shultz Sonoma County Airport."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country in the Indian Ocean is home to an underwater waterfall?",
        "answer": "Mauritius -- Unfortunately, it`s only an optical illusion. What looks like a waterfall when seen from above is actually sand and silt moving along an ocean shelf."
    },
    {
        "question": "What English town is famous for being the supposed burial place of Kimg Arthur?",
        "answer": "Glastonbury -- The king lived and died in Dark Ages Britain, so very little is known about whether he was a mythical legend, or, in fact, a real historical figure."
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent contains the most fresh water?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?",
        "answer": "White Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain range stretches from the town of Seesen in northwest Germany to Eisleben in the east?",
        "answer": "Harz"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Hawaiian island is known as `Bird Island`?",
        "answer": "Nihoa, aka Bird Island or Moku Manu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the fastest flowing river in the world?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was Mozart born?",
        "answer": "Salzburg, Austria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?",
        "answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the northernmost place in the contiguous United States?",
        "answer": "Northwest Angle, Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the iconic Apollo Theater?",
        "answer": "Harlem, New York City"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the first foreign country you would reach if you go south of Detroit, Michigan?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of Djibouti?",
        "answer": "Djibouti City"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the first nation you would reach after heading due east from New York City?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    }
]